CURRICULUM VITAE

I have a few years experience in customer service, and spent 2 years leading a Minecraft Server Project. This is where I realised my passion in programming and development. I have recently graduated from a coding Traineeship as a full stack developer including completing 2 real-world projects successfully to specification using a wide range of programming languages. I possess a strong attention to detail and a natural inclination for problem-solving. Further to this, I have excellent customer service, communication, teamwork and organisation skills and a strong work ethic. I am looking forward to following my passion and establishing a career in the development field where I can prove myself as an asset.

PERSONAL DETAILS

NAME: Gustavo Pereira

RESIDES: London

LANGUAGES: English, Portuguese

RIGHT TO WORK: Spouse Visa

CONTACT DETAILS: (M) 07423 401232

(E) guhenriques1398@gmail.com (W) https://qustavopereira.co.uk/

(GH) https://github.com/guhenriques (please email to request access)

(LI) https://www.linkedin.com/in/guhenriques-1398/

CODING TRAINEESHIP IT Career Switch Ltd

Coding Traineeship – Full stack developer

1-year program

During the traineeship I had to demonstrate a very competent level of the following programming languages and technical skills

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

- PHP, SQL, React, ¡Query
- Python, Node.js, Bootstrap
- Command line Git, Github
- Remote API access

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES:

Express, REST API

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE:

Below are the two briefs of development projects I completed with IT Career Switch which can be found in my bio: https://gustavopereira.co.uk/

Portfolio Project #1: "Gazetteer"

The specification was to reply to a website specification for a map-based app to provide information on countries, with a focus on a "mobile-first" development. Preferably using a framework, to then develop HTML, CSS and JavaScript with JQuery modules that use PHP server-based components to source data from third-party APIs. The solution is assessed on its delivery to specification, functionality, and usability.

Portfolio Project #2: "Company Directory"

A more rigorous reply to this specification was required as a user requirements document was needed to be prepared which, when signed off, triggers the release of SQL allowing to develop a "mobile-first" application to maintain a company personnel database (MySQL). Sign off is only achieved upon the student supplying an independently witnessed document providing confirmation of the system's ability to perform error-free.

CAREER HISTORY:

Jan 2023 – Jun 2023 POSITION HELD:

Tesco Stores Customer Assistant

- Assisted customers on the shop floor
- Restocked shop items and maintained an organised and tidy shop floor
- Managed the in-store bakery
- Received customers at checkout tills and provided assistance with self-checkouts

Nov 2021 – Sep 2022 POSITION HELD:

Grand Hyatt São Paulo Guest Services Agent

- Answered incoming calls promptly and professionally, providing information about hotel services, amenities, and others
- Received and processed guest requests, such as wake-up calls, room service orders, and transportation arrangements
- Responded to guest complaints or concerns and resolved issues promptly and effectively to ensure guest satisfaction
- Demonstrated and promoted a strong commitment to providing the best possible experience for both guests and employees

Sep 2018 – Aug 2021 POSITION HELD:

Hotel Estanplaza Berrini Front Office Team Leader

- Oversaw the day-to-day operations of the front desk and ensured a smooth check-in and check-out process for guests
- Monitored the performance of front desk staff, conducted regular evaluations, and provided feedback for improvement
- Created shift schedules for the front desk team and ensured adequate coverage during peak times
- Enforced hotel policies and procedures to maintain high-quality standards and compliance with safety and security regulations

Jan 2018 – Apr 2020 POSITION HELD:

MundoMinecraft Brasil CEO

- Led a Minecraft Server project with 200 average concurrent players, collaborating with a team of software engineers
- Configured all plugin settings using YML and XML files
- Modified Java-based plugins to add new features and fix issues
- Resolved server bugs by monitoring consoles and logs
- Managed server operations using PUTTY and SSL on Linux
- Collaborated with team members to implement new features and maintain server stability
- Engaged with players to create a positive gaming community
- Assisted in the development and customisation of the wordpress e-commerce platform for in-game purchases and real toy products

Mar 2018 – Sep 2018 POSITION HELD:

Hotel Estanplaza Berrini Front Office Assistant

- Assisted guests with the check-in process, verified identification, and processed payments during check-out
- Managed room bookings, ensured accuracy, and addressed any reservation-related inquiries
- Furnished guests with information about hotel amenities, services, local attractions, and directions
- Attended to guest needs and fulfilled requests promptly and efficiently

Jul 2017 – Feb 2018 POSITION HELD:

Hotel Estanplaza Berrini Bellboy

- Greeted guests upon arrival, helping them with their luggage, and escorting them to their rooms
- Ensured that guests' needs and requests were promptly addressed with a courteous and helpful attitude
- Arranged taxis or other transportation services for guests upon request
- Supported the front desk team during busy periods or when additional assistance was required

EDUCATION: 2020 – 2022

Estacio de Sa University, Brazil Systems Development & Analysis